Finding Aid for Ira M. Smith Papers 1919-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- University of Michigan
  - Other University Activities
    - U-M International Center
      - American Council on "Education, Foreign Universities Project
        - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
        - Report and Proposals, 1946-1950 (Box 9)
      - U.S. Office of Education, Division of International Educational Relations, 1945-1948 (Box 9)
      - National Association of Foreign Student Advisers, 1948 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - U-M Emeritus Club
      - Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 9)
      - Printed material (Box 9)
      - Minutes and annual reports (Box 9)
      - Announcements and Newsletters (Box 9)
    - U-M Alumni Association
      - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
      - Fund-raising reports (Box 9)
      - Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - Pittsburgh Club, 1938-1939 (Box 9)
    - Philadelphia and New York Clubs, 1938-1945 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Club, 1946-1948 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Club, 1938-1949; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Alumni Club Scholarships
      - 1938-1942 (Box 9)
      - 1946 (Box 9)
      - 1947-1950 (Box 9)
    - Alumni "M" Club, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
    - Alumni Advisory Committee, 1939-1949 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - U-M Annuitants Association
      - Correspondence, 1953-1966 (Box 10)
      - Minutes, 1953; 1965-1969 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 10)
    - Studies of Teacher Supply, Demand and Placement in Michigan, 1942-1943; 1946-1947 (Box 10)
    - Bureau of Appointments and Occupational Information
      - Correspondence, 1930-1949; 3 folders (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 10)
      - Diagnostic forms (blanks) (Box 10)
      - Advisory Committee Reports, 1933-1944 (Box 10)
    - Articles (not by Ira Smith) about job placement (Box 10)
    - U-M fraternities and sororities, 1939-1950 (Box 10)
    - Pan-Hellenic Banquets, 1929-1952; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Student Christian Association
      - Histories (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, 1922-1941; 9 folders (Box 10)
      - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1922-1936 (Box 10)
      - Michigan Youth Congress, 1934 (Box 10)
      - University Fresh Air Camp for Boys
        - Papers, 1934-1936 (Box 10)
        - Printed material (Box 10)
      - News Letters, 1935-1936 (Box 10)
      - Freshman Rendezvous Program, 1935-1941 (Box 10)
      - Camp Institute for Freshmen Men, 1941 (Box 10)
      - Financial Reports, 1926-1936; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Caney Creek Community Center, Pippapass, Ky. (Box 10)
      - Report (Box 10)
      - Printed material and programs (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - University athletics
    - Reminiscences of U-M athletics by Ira Smith (Box 11)
    - U-M Board in Control of Physical Education Minutes, 1932-1942 (Box 11)
    - U-M Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics
      - Correspondence, 1932-1962; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Agendas and financial reports, 1933-1942 (Box 11)
      - Annual reports, 1932; 1933; 1940; 1941 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
      - Eligibility Committee
        - Correspondence
          - 1934-1939 (Box 11)
          - 1950-1952 (Box 11)
          - 1953-1959 (Box 11)
        - Eligibility regulations (Box 11)
        - Eligibility lists, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
    - Faculty Inquiry into Intercollegiate Athletics, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Intercollegiate Conference of Faculty Representatives Minutes, 1945-1951 (Box 11)
    - Harry G. Kipke (Papers about), 1937-1943 (Box 11)
    - George A. May (Papers about), 1942 (Box 11)
    - Amos Alonzo Stagg (Papers about), 1961-1965 (Box 11)
    - Physical education for women, 1938-1939 (Box 11)
- Community Activities
  The Community Activities series is further divided into the following subseries: Red Cross - Washtenaw County Chapter; Community Fund; Citizenship Programs; Young Men's Christian Association; Ann Arbor Rotary Club; Ann Arbor Federal Savings and Loan Assoc. Board of Directors; College Admissions Consultation Service; Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce; Boy Scouts of America; and Miscellaneous Organizational Activities.
  - Red Cross-Washtenaw County Chapter
    - Correspondence, 1940-1954 (Box 11)
    - By-Laws (Box 11)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1952-1954 (Box 11)
    - Budgets, 1940; 1951; 1953-1954 (Box 11)
    - National Convention papers, 1952 (Box 11)
    - Fund-raising campaign Papers, 1952; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Fund raising bulletin, 1952 (Box 11)
    - Central Committee on Disaster Preparedness and Relief
      - Correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 11)
      - Memoranda to Chapter Chairmen concerning civil defense, 1942-1944 (Box 11)
      - Sample disaster plans (Box 11)
      - Printed material (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Red Cross--Annual Reports, 1950-1953 (Box 11)
    - News Clippings, 1940-1954 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 11)
  - Community Fund
    - Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 11)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 11)
    - Papers concerning Fund Drives
      - 1941-1944 (Box 11)
      - 1955-1958 (Box 11)
    - Annual Reports, 1944; 1947; 1948; 1952 (Box 11)
  - Citizenship Programs
    - Washtenaw County Citizenship Day Papers, 1940 (Box 11)
    - University of Wisconsin Citizenship Training Program Papers, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Young Men's Christian Association
    - YMCA--National Committee
      - National Council meeting papers
        - 1957 (Box 12)
        - 1959, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - National Board Meetings, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - YMCA--State Committee
      - History (Box 12)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1971; 7 folders (Box 12)
      - Minutes, 1943-1965 (Box 12)
      - State Committee Meeting, 1959; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Trip reports, 1962 (Box 12)
      - State convention programs, 1945-1960 (Box 12)
      - Advisory Committee Minutes, September 1958 (Box 12)
      - Laymen's Conference Programs, 1944-1957 (Box 12)
      - Board of Trustees
        - Minutes, 1965-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Memoranda, 1965-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1965-1969 (Box 12)
      - Executive Committee
        - Minutes, 1945-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Memoranda, 1965-1968 (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1966-1968 (Box 12)
        - Annual report, 1936 (Box 12)
      - Harmon Davies, Associate State Secretary, papers, 1957 (Box 12)
      - Roger Blood, Associate State Secretary, papers, 1957-1958 (Box 12)
      - Financial papers, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Reference materials (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous papers (Box 12)
      - State Student committee
        - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
        - Minutes, 1944-1951 (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
      - State Youth Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
      - Program Services Committee
        - Correspondence, undated; 1951; 1954-1958; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Memoranda, 1951 (Box 12)
        - Minutes, 1951-1958 (Box 12)
        - Samples of Club activities (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
      - Organizational study commission papers, undated (Box 12)
      - Administrative Finance Committee
        - Correspondence, 1956-1959; 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Memoranda, 1956-1958 (Box 12)
        - Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 12)
      - Professional Education Committee, 1958 (Box 12)
      - Committee on Higher Education
        - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 12)
        - Minutes and Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 12)
      - Recruitment and Personnel Committee
        - Correspondence, 1958; 2 folders (Box 13)
        - Memoranda, 1956-1957 (Box 13)
        - Minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 13)
        - Recruiting Kit (Box 13)
        - Printed materials (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 13)
      - Personnel Selection Committee
        - Memoranda, 1967 (Box 13)
        - Minutes, 1945-1946 (Box 13)
      - Legal Affairs Committee Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 13)
      - International Committee Papers, 1957 (Box 13)
      - Agenda Committee Papers, 1956-1957 (Box 13)
      - World Service Building Committee
        - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1957 (Box 13)
      - Committee on Elections and Procedures Papers, 1957 (Box 13)
      - Committee on Membership and Membership Policies, 1957 (Box 13)
      - Credentials Committee Papers, 1958 (Box 13)
      - Committee on the Constitution
        - Papers, 1957-1960 (Box 13)
        - Constitutions and By-Laws. Draft, 3, 1924-1958 (Box 13)
        - Constitutions and By-Laws. Drafts, undated; 1959-1960 (Box 13)
      - Committee on Interracial Policies and Programs, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Public Affairs Committee Papers, 1943-1955 (Box 13)
      - Human Relations Committee Papers, 1954 (Box 13)
      - Commission on work with women and girls Papers, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
      - Workshop on the Inner City, 1965 (Box 13)
      - Work with U.S.O., 1943 (Box 13)
      - YMCA Veteran Services, 1942-1945 (Box 13)
      - Pre-Induction Education for American Servicemen, 1955 (Box 13)
      - Older Boys Conferences
        - 1941-1944 (Box 13)
        - 1957 (Box 13)
      - Youth Legislatures
        - Papers, 1956 (Box 13)
        - Printed material, 1950-1956 (Box 13)
        - Book of Bills, 1952 (Box 13)
      - Wolverine Boys' State, 1938-1940 (Box 13)
      - YMCA work with Adult Education Assoc. of Michigan, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
      - John R. Mott Fellowship Fund, 1956 (Box 13)
      - Club Handbook, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - YMCA Centennial, 1944 (Box 13)
      - YMCA Camp Announcements (Box 13)
      - Camp Committee Minutes, 1965; 1969 (Box 13)
      - Camp Hayo-Went-Ha, 1965-1967 (Box 13)
      - Tri-County Meetings, 1958 (Box 13)
      - Upper Peninsula District YMCA, 1947-1948 (Box 13)
      - Town, Country and Extension Committee
        - Meeting papers, 1955-1958 (Box 13)
        - Program descriptions, 1951-1960 (Box 13)
        - Town, Country & Extension Bulletin, 1955-1959 (Box 13)
      - Michigan, Ohio, W. Virginia YMCA Regional Agreement, 1969 (Box 13)
    - YMCA--Local Chapters
      - Adrian, 1957-1961 (Box 14)
      - Ann Arbor
        - A Study of the Young Men's Christian Association of Ann Arbor, Mi., 1953 (Box 14)
        - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 14)
        - Correspondence, 1940-1946; 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Board of Directors
          - Minutes, 1941-1956; 2 folders (Box 14)
          - Lists of Board Members & Trustees, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
        - Annual Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 14)
        - General Membership lists (Box 14)
        - YMCA-Community Fund Work, 1943 (Box 14)
        - YM-YW Building Amalgamation Committee
          - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 14)
          - Reports, 1954; 1956 (Box 14)
        - World Service Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 14)
        - Men's Club, 1954 (Box 14)
        - Financial papers, 1921-1944 (Box 14)
        - News clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Battle Creek, 1957-1959 (Box 14)
      - Bay City, 1957-1963 (Box 14)
      - Benton Harbor-St. Joseph, 1967 (Box 14)
      - Detroit, 1958-1959 (Box 14)
      - Du, 1957 (Box 14)
      - Flint, 1957-1959 (Box 14)
      - Grand Rapids, 1958-1959 (Box 14)
      - Hillsdale, 1957-1965 (Box 14)
      - Holland-Zee, 1960-1963 (Box 14)
      - Jackson, 1956-1962 (Box 14)
      - Kalamazoo, 1958-1966 (Box 14)
      - Lansing, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
      - Monroe
        - Correspondence, 1958-1965 (Box 14)
        - Newsletters, 1961-1963 (Box 14)
        - Joint program with the S.E. Michigan Industrial Management Club, 1960-1962 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1960-1965 (Box 14)
      - Muskegon, 1958 (Box 14)
      - Niles, 1958 (Box 14)
      - Owosso, 1958 (Box 14)
      - Pontiac, 1963 (Box 14)
      - Port Huron, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
      - Saginaw, 1951-1957 (Box 14)
      - Proposal for Extension of YMCA Services to Genesee and Lapeer Counties, May 11, 1967 (Box 14)
    - YMCA--Chicago Central YMCA Schools
      - Histories, 1920-1925 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Box 14)
      - Board of Governors
        - Minutes, 1924-1926 (Box 14)
        - Reports, 1924-1925 (Box 14)
      - Financial papers, 1924-1926 (Box 14)
      - Policy Statements, 1925; 1927 (Box 14)
      - Printed materials (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1925-1927 (Box 14)
    - YMCA Publications
      - Intercollegian, 1955-1956 (Box 14)
      - Association Work (Box 14)
      - National Council Bulletin, 1942-1943; 1954-1959; 1965 (Box 14)
      - National Hi-Y Ways, 1957-1959 (Box 14)
      - After the Whistle Blows, 1950 (Box 14)
      - Christian Businessmen's Contact, 1951 (Box 14)
      - YMCA State Newsletter, 1944-1958; 6 folders (Box 15)
      - Printed materials, 8 folders (Box 15)
    - YMCA--Miscellaneous papers, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Michigan YMCA--Annual Reports, 1939-1952 (Box 15)
    - Michigan YMCA--Annual Reports, 1953-1960 (Box 16)
  - Ann Arbor Rotary Club
    - Histories (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1969; 21 folders (Box 16)
    - Correspondence not by Ira Smith, 1934-1938 (Box 16)
    - Papers, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Membership lists (Box 16)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 16)
    - Program Committee
      - Correspondence (Ira Smith's), 1926-1947; 8 folders (Box 17)
      - Correspondence (not Ira Smith's), 1926-1931; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Programs, 1943-1966; 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous papers
        - 1929-1931 (Box 17)
        - 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Secretary's papers, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Treasurer's papers, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Aims and Objects Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Youth Service Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - International Service Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Classification Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Community Service Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Vocational Service Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Crippled Children Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Papers concerning attendance, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Membership and Classification Committee
      - 1929 (Box 17)
      - 1941 (Box 17)
    - Student Loan Funds Committee, 1941 (Box 17)
    - Club Service Committee (Box 17)
    - Committee on Study of Aims and Programs Papers, 1946 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Club Committee reports (Box 17)
    - Reports to the District Governor concerning Club Committees, 1964-1965 (Box 17)
    - Treasurers' Reports, 1927; 1928; 1962; 1966 (Box 17)
    - District International Conference, 1932 (Box 17)
    - Annual Convention, 1934 (Box 17)
    - Mexico City Convention, 1935 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous conference Papers, 1935-1936 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous conference papers, 1941-1942 (Box 17)
    - Speeches delivered at Rotary Conferences, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Newsclippings, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Information Sheets for local clubs (Box 17)
    - Printed material, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Governor's Monthly Letter
      - 1926-1930 (Box 17)
      - 1934-1936, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Ann Arbor Federal Savings and Loan Assoc. Board of Directors
    - Correspondence, 1939-1969 (Box 18)
    - U.S. Savings and Loan League Policies, 1940-1952 (Box 18)
    - News Clippings (Box 18)
    - Printed materials (Box 18)
    - Financial reports
      - 1939-1953 (Box 18)
      - 1956-1967 (Box 18)
    - Minutes, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 18)
  - College Admissions Consultation Service
    - Correspondence, 1954-1964; 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Announcements and newsclippings (Box 18)
    - Papers concerning the Student Aid Foundation of Michigan (Box 18)
    - Pathway to College, by Fred Stevenson and Ira Smith (Box 18)
    - Papers concerning filmstrip, "Looking Ahead to College", 1955-1956 (Box 18)
    - College guidance pamphlets by Ira Smith, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous writings about college by Ira Smith (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce
    - Correspondence, 1933-1959; 8 folders (Box 18)
    - Board of Directors Minutes, 1940-1941; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, February 1941 (Box 18)
    - Ann Arbor Student Housing Survey, 1934 (Box 18)
    - Secretary's Reports, 1940 (Box 18)
    - Financial Statements, 1939-1941 (Box 18)
    - News Clippings (Box 18)
    - Junior Chamber of Commerce Reports, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Boy Scouts of America
    - National Council papers, 1947-1969 (Box 19)
    - Washtenaw-Livingston Council
      - Correspondence (Ira Smith's), 1935-1960; 11 folders (Box 19)
      - Correspondence (not Ira Smith's), 1940-1957; 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Executive Board Minutes, 1944-1951; 5 folders (Box 19)
      - Executive Committee Minutes, 1952-1963; 3 folders (Box 19)
      - Local Council Report to Regional Office (Box 19)
      - Financial papers, 1940-1962; 4 folders (Box 19)
      - Rural Scouting, 1935-1939 (Box 19)
      - World Friendship Fund, 1945 (Box 19)
      - Regional cooperation, 1956-1957 (Box 19)
      - Portage Trails Notes, 1951-1966 (Box 19)
      - The Whole Scout Family, 1947-1950 (Box 19)
      - Around the Council, 1949-1951 (Box 19)
      - Clippings (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 6 folders (Box 19)
      - Printed material (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Organizational Activities
    - Ann Arbor Council of Churches, 1937-1944 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Council of Churches and Christian Education
      - Correspondence, 1942-1945; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Annual meeting Reports, 1940; 1944 (Box 19)
      - Reports of the Executive Secretary, 1944 (Box 19)
      - Christian Family Life Program (Box 19)
      - Articles concerning religious education in public schools (Box 19)
      - Programs and announcements (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1939-1945; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Ann Arbor Youth Hostel Council, 1945-1946 (Box 19)
    - Optimist Breakfast Club, 1957 (Box 19)
    - Thursday's Luncheon Club, 1966-1968 (Box 19)
    - Ann Arbor Senior Citizen's Guild
      - Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1956-1959 (Box 19)
    - Citizens for Michigan, 1959 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Christian Junior College, 1960-1963 (Box 19)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series consists of two envelopes of images and includes photographs of Smith and co-workers at annual Christmas parties and of Smith with colleagues at various professional meetings. There are also negatives of University buildings and students, of activities at the University Elementary School in Ann Arbor, Michigan, and of women's athletics, presumably at the University of Michigan (ca. 1920s). Illustrative of Smith's community involvement are group portraits of a Boy Scout troop (1943) at Camp Newkirk (Webster Township, Michigan) and of staff and campers at Ann Arbor YMCA's Camp Birkett.
  - Portraits (Box 19)
  - Groups (Box 19)